JEREMY CLOUGH

SOFTWARE SUPPORT ENGINEER

Newbury, RG14

\sim	\sim		^	_
		114	ΛС.	

PROFILE

https://ripley57.github.io/jeremyclough/

git https://github.com/ripley57

EXONAR

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremy-clough-40a08415

Self-learner who relishes troubleshooting software issues. Skilled at diving deep into code when the need arises, to determine how things work and why they don't. Enjoys writing tools to demonstrate issues and to accelerate daily activities. A team player who proactively shares knowledge with team members. Takes pride in building a strong rapport with customers, developers and documentation teams. Experienced in working within an Agile SDLC.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF BIRMINGHAM

Mechanical Engineering 2.1 MEng (Hons)

Edgbaston, Birmingham B15 2TT (1992 - 1996)

Final Year Project: Implementation of a preemptive multi-tasking OS written in Motorola 68000 assembly language.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Newbury, RG14 5HG

INTEGRATION AND SUPPORT ENGINEER

(FEB 2019 - JUNE 2019)

Member of a team of four providing customer support for a bespoke software and hardware BigData search solution to enable organisations to identify sensitive and other PII data, helping them comply with regulatory requirements including GDPR. Working closely with developer, DevOps and test teams, investigated customer issues, in addition to configuration and performance problems. Performed acceptance testing before shipping and carred out onsite installation and ongoing visits.

Skills: Linux (CentOS), scripting (Bash), Java, PSQL, Linux Containers.

VERITAS / SYMANTEC

350 Brook Dr, Reading RG2 6UH

ADVANCED TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER

(MAR 2012 - JAN 2019)

Assisted customers using the Veritas eDiscovery Platform, software that implements the complete EDRM model by providing advanced document discovery and searching capabilities for legal teams and other digital forensics professionals. The platform is based around a Tomcat web server with supporting Java MBean-based services, running on Windows server.

Acting as a combined Backline Engineer and Technical Team Lead, became the go-to person in the UK support team, described by management as "the team's rock". Reviewed Frontline support escalations to the Engineering team, preventing them where possible. Mentored team members, sharing self-taught product knowledge and taking ownership of product bugs to report them to Engineering, often with a tested coded solution (Java).

Created a framework of tools comprised of numerous self-written utilities, to provide an instant working environment for accelerating the investigation of product problems. The toolset included: MAPI utilities to interrogate and generate/edit email data; scripts and tooling to automate the generation of large test datasets; scripts to setup a customised Eclipse debugging environment; demos of various software technologies used by the product, for self-learning and reproduction cut-downs.

Received award for helping retain a million dollar customer support renewal with a major UK/US bank, by investigating each of their top issues to code level, providing weekly reports with detailed explanations to the customer and bug reports to the Engineering team. Received praise from the customer for going above and beyond: "Jeremy goes the extra mile to resolve our incidents, often writing his own scripts and really getting into the details of what is causing the incidents".

As a Knowledgebase Publisher, reviewed technical articles written by other team members, validating them for accuracy before publication. Submitted detailed reports to the documentation team for any inaccuracies or omissions. Received award from the documentation team for being one of their favourite contributors "often prompting incisive discussions not only with the doc team but with development and product QA as well".

Skills: Ajax, Java, JavaScript, Tomcat, C/C++, MAPI, Perl, Windows (batch) scripting, MySQL, PKI/SSL, LDAP, Windows Server 2008/2012.

BARRACUDA NETWORKS

Basingstoke, Hampshire, RG22 6HY

TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER

(FEB 2010 - FEB 2012)

Member of a team of five, providing support to customers using the Barracuda Spam & Virus Firewall and Barracuda Backup appliances; hardware and software solutions for Linux utilising a combination of bespoke and open source software.

Investigated customer issues remotely, troubleshooting problems to source code level (mostly Perl). Reported bugs, with reproduction steps, to the Engineering team, researching and implementing workarounds for the customer where possible.

Skills: Linux, Perl, Postfix MTA, SMTP, Amavis, Apache, ClamAV, SpamAssassin, DNS/MX records.

MICRO FOCUS LTD

The Lawn, 22-30 Old Bath Rd, Newbury RG14 1QN

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

(JAN 2009 - AUG 2009)

Followed agile development practices (Scrum) as a member of the Core development team, investigating issues with the COBOL debugger and COBOL runtime (C/C++). Worked on the implementation of UNIX/Linux support in the COBOL debugger for executables compiled with DWARF debugging information. Helped maintain the team's automated test suite.

Skills: C development on UNIX/Linux, gdb, COBOL

SENIOR UNIX SOFTWARE RELEASE ENGINEER

(APR 2003 - DEC 2008)

Produced builds and Fix packs for the Server Express product. UNIX variants included: IBM AIX, Compaq Tru64, HP-UX (PA-RISC, Itanium), Red Hat (x86-64, PPC, 390), Solaris (Intel, Sparc), SuSE (x86-64, PPC, 390) and SCO UnixWare.

Formed strong relationships with the developers, helping them integrate new software components into the build. Provided ongoing assistance for developers when investigating their customer issues, particularly those less experienced with UNIX/Linux.

Co-ordinated ports of the Server Express product to new Linux releases. Fed back code changes necessary to resolve build and runtime issues to the relevant developers. Worked with Core Engineering team to integrate lower-level assembly pieces.

Ensured the availability of daily product builds for the developers, including a long period when transitioning to a major new in-house continuous build (CI) system. Rotated team duties in order to investigate issues with the new build system while still maintaining daily builds for developers and GA builds for customer Fix packs, GA product releases and POCs.

Skills: UNIX/Linux administration, Make, Imake, Ant, Perl, CVS, Subversion, UNIX scripting.

COMPAQ COMPUTER LTD / HEWLETT PACKARD

Worton Grange, Imperial Way, Reading, RG2 OTE

SYSTEMS DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

(JUN 1999 - AUG 2002)

Worked with Software Architects in the Telecoms practice, implementing network management software solutions for major companies including Vodafone, Alcatel, Cable & Wireless, and BT.

With no prior training, owned and maintained several TeMIP GAT Access Module software components, used for monitoring network hardware faults. Fixed many legacy issues, helping the team achieve a significant customer payment milestone for the Vodafone NMI Project. Received an Outstanding Contribution Award in recognition of this work and for helping regain the customer's confidence.

Instigated the use of source code control (RCS) during a project where it was not being used. Became the project's build coordinator, automating the creation of reproducible builds and packaging directly from RCS. Created a tool for Project Management to generate HTML to quickly see the code changes between each build.

Skills: C/C++ Programming, UNIX (Compaq Tru64), RCS, Tcl/Tk, TeMIP, UNIX scripting.

KERRIDGE COMPUTER COMPANY LIMITED

Northcroft Lane, Newbury, RG14 1HT

UNIX SOFTWARE ENGINEER

(SEP 1996 - SEP 1997)

Implemented tooling to parse SQL data dictionary files and generate corresponding ISAM databases. Added new features to the KCML programming editor to enable users to manage CVS merge conflicts in their source files.

Skills: C Programming, Lex/Yacc, UNIX, KCML